<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code on</title><link>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/</link><description>Recent content in Code on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:43:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Dictionary Creator</title><link>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/datadictionarycreator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:31:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/datadictionarycreator/</guid><description>My first Python package, adamic, is a simple solution for creating data dictionaries.
Installation # The package is available on PyPi and can be downloaded by running the following from the command line:
pip install adamic Use # After installing the package to your environment, import the package to your script, Jupyter notebook, or directly to the python3 command line.
from adamic import adamic To create your data dictionary, pass a Pandas dataframe to the create_data_dictionary() function:</description></item><item><title>Exploratory Data Analysis</title><link>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/exploratorydataanalysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 01:05:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/exploratorydataanalysis/</guid><description>Double-click the README.md in the interactive window for more information.
For other examples of my data science projects, see this GitHub repository.</description></item><item><title>Fetch Current Weather</title><link>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/fetchweatherscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 23:34:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/fetchweatherscript/</guid><description>I like knowing the weather as soon as I get up in the morning. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t always like poking my head outside to find out, and a simple Google search doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide me all the weather details I want to know directly in the search returns page. So I wrote a Python script that gives me exactly what I want. Because I&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally travel, I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up so that, rather than simply defaulting to my primary location, I can enter the name of the city for which I want the weather details.</description></item><item><title>RenText</title><link>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/rentext/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 22:31:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://benbarksdale.netlify.app/code/rentext/</guid><description>RenText is my ongoing effort to use computational tools to study Renaissance English texts, published roughly from 1470-1700.
Data Overview # The data used in this project is from the Text Creation Partnership.
The primary data currently consists of approximately 60,000 XML files, which can be accessed on the TCP&amp;rsquo;s Dropbox.
As described on this page, all of the 60K+ texts were hand-coded over the course of about 20 years. The exact nature of the EEBO source texts—digitized (often quite old and occasionally poor-quality) microfilm of original hard copies—made and continues to make optical character recognition infeasible.</description></item></channel></rss>